redbox.com 2013-12-12

# Redbox Privacy Policy | Redbox customer Privcay Policy

The Effective Date of this Privacy Policy is May 22nd 2013.

This Privacy Policy applies to the Redbox web sites that post this policy (including, without limitation, Redbox.com) (each a “ **Site** ”), and to information collected through Redbox kiosks and Redbox mobile applications, including any available interactive features, downloads, applications, widgets or other outlets made available through a Redbox web site or that interact with a Redbox web site, and that post or include a link to this Privacy Policy, regardless of whether accessed via computer, mobile device or otherwise (collectively, the “ **Redbox Platforms** ”). The Redbox Platforms are owned or controlled by Redbox Automated Retail, LLC (doing business in Texas as DVD Rental by Redbox LLC) (“ **Redbox** ,” “ **we** ” or “ **us** ”). This Privacy Policy only covers information collected on the Redbox Platforms and does not cover any information collected at any other web site or elsewhere by Redbox (unless specifically stated). This Privacy Policy explains Redbox’s information collection practices, such as the types of information Redbox collects and how we may use that information. Please review this Privacy Policy carefully. In addition, please review the **_[Terms of Use](http://www.redbox.com/terms)_** , which governs your use of the Redbox Platforms, and the **_[Redbox Rental Terms](http://www.redbox.com/rentalterms)_** , which explains the rules for renting or reserving any item from Redbox.

**TABLE OF CONTENTS**

    * [Information Third Parties Provide About You and Social Media Interactions](http://www.redbox.com/privacy#anchor7)

  * [COMMUNITY FORUMS, USER CONTENT AND POSTING INFORMATION THROUGH OUR PLATFORMS](http://www.redbox.com/privacy#anchor9)
    * [When You Agree to Receive Information From Third Parties or Otherwise Request That We Share Your Information](http://www.redbox.com/privacy#anchor11)
  * YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS
  * [CHANGING YOUR INFORMATION AND UPDATING YOUR PREFERENCES AND SUBSCRIPTIONS](http://www.redbox.com/privacy#anchor17)
  * [THIRD PARTY CONTENT, LINKS TO THIRD PARTY SITES AND REDBOX CONTENT FOUND ON THIRD PARTY SITES](http://www.redbox.com/privacy#anchor18)

**OVERVIEW**

**WE FULLY DESCRIBE OUR PRIVACY PRACTICES BELOW IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY.   THIS OVERVIEW HIGHLIGHTS SOME IMPORTANT INFORMATION REGARDING THIRD PARTY ADVERTISERS AND OUR USE AND SHARING OF YOUR INFORMATION, BUT PLEASE REVIEW OUR FULL PRIVACY POLICY BEFORE USING OUR SITE.**  
**REDBOX WORKS WITH NETWORK ADVERTISERS, AD AGENCIES AND OTHER VENDORS TO SERVE REDBOX ADS ON THIRD PARTY WEB SITES AND ACROSS THE INTERNET. YOU MAY ALSO SEE THIRD PARTY ADS ON THE SITE. THESE OTHER COMPANIES MAY COLLECT CERTAIN INFORMATION ABOUT YOUR VISITS TO THIS OR OTHER WEB SITES IN CONNECTION WITH SERVING ADVERTISEMENTS.   WE DO NOT SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH THESE THIRD PARTIES, BUT AD NETWORK PROVIDERS, THE ADVERTISERS, AD AGENCIES, ANALYTICS SERVICE PROVIDERS AND OTHER VENDORS MAY SET AND ACCESS THEIR OWN TRACKING DEVICES (INCLUDING _[COOKIES](http://www.redbox.com/privacy#cookies)_ ) AND THEY MAY OTHERWISE COLLECT OR HAVE ACCESS TO INFORMATION ABOUT YOU.  FOR MORE INFORMATION, CLICK _[HERE](http://www.redbox.com/privacy#anchor16)_. **

**WITH REGARD TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION, WE PRI MARILY USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN CONNECTION WITH YOUR RELATIONSHIP WITH REDBOX, YOUR USE OF THE PLATFORMS, AND FOR COMPLETING YOUR TRANSACTIONS ON THE PLATFORMS. CLICK[HERE](http://www.redbox.com/privacy#anchor3) FOR THE FULL DESCRIPTION OF THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT. PLEASE REMEMBER THAT IF YOU PARTICIPATE IN FORUMS AND OTHER SOCIAL NETWORKING FEATURES ON THE PLATFORMS, YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE MADE PUBLIC AND THE VIDEO PRIVACY PROTECTION ACT (OR SIMILAR STATE LAWS) DOES NOT APPLY. NOTE THAT WE DO NOT SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES FOR THEIR MARKETING PURPOSES UNLESS YOU CONSENT TO SUCH SHARING BUT WE DO SHARE WITH THIRD PARTIES UNDER CERTAIN LIMITED CIRCUMSTANCES – CLICK [HERE](http://www.redbox.com/privacy#anchor10) FOR MORE DETAILS REGARDING WHEN WE MAY SHARE INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES.**

**CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY POLICY**

Redbox reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time without notice to you. Any changes will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy. However, Redbox will not use your Personal Information in a manner materially different than what was stated at the time it was collected without your consent.

**THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT**

**Information You Provide Us**

We may ask you to provide personally identifiable information, which is information that identifies you as a specific individual, such as your name, phone number, e-mail address or payment information (collectively, “ **Personal Information** ”), and other information about you, such as demographic information (for example, your gender, age or similar information). Certain features may also collect information about your preferences and interests. If we combine demographic, preference-related or similar information with the Personal Information we collect, we will treat it as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

Please note that information submitted to a “contact us” or other similar function may not receive a response. We will not use the information provided via these functions to contact you for marketing purposes unrelated to your request unless we disclose otherwise at the time you submit the request.

**Information You Provide About Some One Else**

If you send someone else a communication from the Redbox Platforms, such as sending content to a friend, the information you provide (for example, names, e-mail addresses, etc.) is used on a one-time basis to facilitate the communication and is not used for any other marketing purpose unless we obtain consent from that person.

**Information We Collect Automatically**

We and our third-party service providers may use a variety of technologies that automatically or passively collect certain information whenever you visit or interact with us or our content found elsewhere on the internet (“ **Usage Information** ”). Usage Information may include the browser and operating system you are using, the URL or advertisement that referred you to our Site or content, all of the areas within our Site that you visit, including items that you browse, the time of day, and the preceding page viewed, among other information. We may use Usage Information for a variety of purposes, including to enhance or otherwise improve the Site and our services.  In addition, we automatically collect your IP address or other unique identifier (“ **Device Identifier** ”) for any computer, mobile phone or other device (any, a “ **Device** ”) you may use to access our Site or mobile application. A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your Device used to access our Site or mobile application, and our servers identify your Device by its Device Identifier. When you download and use our mobile application, we also collect information about your mobile device, including the hardware model, operating system and version, mobile network information, time zone and location information.  . Please note that you have the ability to stop Redbox's collection of location information at any time by changing the settings on your Device or by following the standard uninstall process and removing our mobile application from your Device. Usage Information is generally non-identifying, but if Redbox associates it with you as a specific and identifiable person, Redbox treats it as Personal Information.  

The methods that may be used to collect Usage Information include the following:

_**Cookies**_. A cookie is a data file placed on a Device when it is used to visit a Site or otherwise access our online content. Cookies may be used for many purposes, including, without limitation, remembering you and your preferences and tracking your visits to our web pages. A Flash cookie is a data file placed on a Device via the Adobe Flash plugin that may be built-in to or downloaded by you to your Device.  Flash cookies may be used for various purposes, including, without limitation, enabling a Flash feature and remembering your preferences. For more information about Flash and the privacy choices Adobe offers, visit _<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html>_. If you choose to disable cookies or to adjust your Flash privacy settings on your Device, some features of a Site may not function properly.

_**Web Beacons**_. Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as “1x1 GIFs” or “clear GIFs”), may be included in our web pages and e-mail messages. Web beacons may be invisible to you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a web page or e-mail can act as a web beacon. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to a Site, to monitor how users navigate a Site, to count how many e-mails that were sent were actually opened or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed.

_**Embedded Scripts**_. An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with a Site, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your Device from our web server or a third party service provider, is active only while you are connected to a Site, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

We may also record information regarding the use of our Kiosks. This information is typically non-identifying, but if it is identifiable to you as a specific person, we will treat it as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy. 

**Information Third Parties Provide About You and Social Media Interactions**

Redbox may receive information about you from third parties. For example, if you are on another web site and you agree to receive information from Redbox, that web site will forward your contact and other information to us so that we may contact you as requested. You may also choose to participate in a third party application or feature (such as one of our Facebook applications or a similar application or feature on a third party web site) through which you post content or allow us to collect (or the third party to share) information about you, including Personal Information. The third party may allow you to remove the application or feature, in which case we will no longer collect information about you through the application or feature, but we may retain the information previously collected.  In addition, we may receive information about you if other users of a third party web site give us access to their profiles and you are one of their “connections” or information about you is otherwise accessible through your “connections” web page, profile page, or similar page on a social networking or other third party web site, application or interactive service. 

We also may verify or supplement the information we collect with outside records from third parties in order to provide you with information, services or goods you have requested, to enhance our ability to serve you, to tailor our content to you and to offer you opportunities to purchase products or services that we believe may be of interest to you.  We may combine the information we receive from those other sources with information we collect through the Redbox Platforms. In those cases, we will apply this Privacy Policy to the combined information.

**Our Use of Information Collected Through the Platforms**

Redbox may use information collected through the Redbox Platforms, including your Personal Information, to: (1) allow you to participate in features we offer or to provide related customer service, including, without limitation, to respond to your questions, complaints or comments; (2) tailor content recommendations and offers we display to you; (3) process a rental or other transaction you initiate; (4) provide you with information, products or services that you have requested or that we think may interest you; (5) process your registration, including verifying your e-mail address is active and valid; (6) improve the Redbox Platforms or our services and for internal business purposes; (7) facilitate your job search via the Redbox Platforms and prepare related governmental and internal statistics reports; (8) contact you with regard to your use of the Redbox Platforms and, in our discretion, changes to the Redbox Platform policies; and (9) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your Personal Information or otherwise with your consent.

**COMMUNITY FORUMS, USER CONTENT AND POSTING INFORMATION THROUGH OUR PLATFORMS**

The Redbox Platforms may offer message boards, chat rooms and other public areas (collectively, “ **Community Forums** ”) where you can engage in social networking, interact with others, and in some cases choose to submit photographs, writings, music, video, audio recordings, computer graphics, pictures, data, questions, comments, suggestions or other content, including Personal Information (collectively, “ **User Content** ”).

_**Note that anything you post to a Community Forum is public**_ **.** Others will have access to your User Content and may use it or share it with third parties.  Information you choose to post or make available in the Community Forums may be viewed, collected and used by others.  If you choose to voluntarily disclose User Content, the protections of this Privacy Policy will not cover your disclosure of that information or content. Think carefully before you post and use caution before disclosing any Personal Information. In addition, you acknowledge that if you post your User Content to a Community Forum, including any information about your movie or other rentals, you are choosing to do so and the Video Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (18 U.S.C. § 2710) (or any similar state law) does not apply.  However, to the extent it does apply in any manner, you are providing your informed, written consent to the disclosure of that information pursuant to the Video Privacy Protection Act.

**User Content may be published by Redbox online or offline in any media or format (currently existing or hereafter developed).   Subject to applicable law, we may also publish your name, voice, likeness and other Personal Information with your User Content, and Redbox may use the content, or any portion of the content, for advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities.  **For full terms and conditions regarding User Content you submit, please review our **_[Terms of Use](http://www.redbox.com/terms)_**.

And, if you choose to “like” content on a Site or to otherwise post information from or via the Redbox Platforms to a third party web site, feature or application, that information will become public and the third party web site may have access to information about you and your use of our Web Site. 

**HOW AND WHEN WE DISCLOSE INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES**

Redbox may share non-personally identifiable information, such as aggregated user statistics or a Redbox identification or transaction number, with third parties. We do not share your Personal Information with third parties for those third parties’ marketing purposes unless you consent to such sharing at the time you provide your Personal Information. We may share the information we have collected about you, including Personal Information, as disclosed at the time you provide your information, as described in this Privacy Policy, and in the following circumstances:

**When You Agree to Receive Information From Third Parties or Otherwise Request That We Share Your Information**

You may be presented with an opportunity to receive information and/or marketing offers from one or more third parties. If you agree at that time to have your Personal Information shared, your Personal Information will be disclosed to that third party (or parties) and will be subject to the privacy policy and practices of that third party. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of third parties and, therefore, you should review the privacy policies and practices of third parties prior to agreeing to share your information. If you later decide that you no longer want to receive communications from a third party, you will need to contact that third party directly.  If you are a California resident, please see "Your California Privacy Rights" below for more information.

You also may request, sometimes through your use of an interactive feature or third party application, that we share information about you with a third party and we will typically do so under those circumstances.  For example, we may share information with third parties regarding a purchase you make at Redbox in order for you to receive an online credit or points or to be able to play an interactive game on a third party web site, interactive feature or application.

**Third Parties Providing Services on Our Behalf**

We may use third party vendors to perform certain services on our behalf, such as hosting a Site, designing and operating a Site’s features, providing consumer affairs services, fulfilling and processing orders, assisting with promotions, tracking analytics, enabling Redbox to send you e-mail, or performing other administrative services. We may provide these companies with access to user information, including Personal Information, to carry out the services they are performing for you or for Redbox.

**When You Purchase Tickets**

We may share and receive information from certain third parties when you purchase tickets from the Redbox Platforms.  For example, we work with Accertify, Inc., a provider of fraud management solutions, to process ticket orders and prevent fraudulent transactions. When these entities collect information about you, they will treat such information in accordance with their own privacy policies. We may also share information about you and your tickets transactions with the applicable venues and/or ticket sellers in order to process your transactions and for their own recordkeeping, analytics and other internal business purposes.

**Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions**

We may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions (any, a “Promotion”) that may require registration. By participating in a Promotion, you are agreeing to the terms, conditions or official rules that govern that Promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor(s) of the Promotion to use your name, voice, likeness or other indicia of persona in advertising or marketing associated with the Promotion. If you choose to enter a Promotion, Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties or the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, including, without limitation, in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, and as required by law or permitted by the Promotion’s official rules, such as on a winners list.

**Administrative and Legal Reasons**

We may also transfer and disclose user information, including Personal Information, to third parties: (i) in the event we are required to respond to subpoenas or other legal process or if in our opinion such disclosure is required by law; (ii) at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; or (iii) to protect and/or defend the [Terms of Use](http://www.redbox.com/terms), the Redbox [Rental Terms](http://www.redbox.com/rentalterms) or other policies applicable to a Site or our services or to protect the personal safety, rights, property or security of Redbox or any individual. We may also use Device Identifiers, including IP addresses, to identify users, and may do so in cooperation with copyright owners, Internet service providers, wireless service providers or law enforcement agencies in our discretion. These disclosures may be carried out without notice to you.

**Business Transfers**

Redbox may share Personal Information with its parent, Outerwall, Inc., or its subsidiaries and affiliates, primarily for business and operational purposes. Redbox also reserves the right to disclose and transfer all information related to a Site, our mobile applications and our Kiosks, including Personal Information: (i) to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of a Site or applicable database; or (ii) in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of certain of Redbox’s ownership interests, assets, or both, or other company change, including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process.

**THIRD PARTY CONTENT, ANALYTICS PROVIDERS AND AD SERVERS**

Redbox works with network advertisers, ad agencies and other vendors to serve Redbox ads on third party web sites and across the Internet and we use analytics providers to provide us with information regarding the use of the Redbox Platforms and the effectiveness of the advertisements that we place elsewhere on the Internet, in third party applications or elsewhere. You may also see third party ads on the site and those ads may be served by a third party. These other companies may collect certain information about your visits to this or other web sites in connection with serving advertisements and providing us with analytics information.  We do not share personal information with these third parties, but ad network providers, the advertisers, ad agencies, analytics service providers and other vendors may set and access their own tracking technologies on your Device (including [cookies](http://www.redbox.com/privacy#cookies) and [web beacons](http://www.redbox.com/privacy#beacons)) and they may otherwise collect or have access to information about you, including Usage Information.

Cookies and web beacons, including those set by third party network advertisers, may be used to, among other things, target advertisements, prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times and to conduct research regarding the usefulness of certain advertisements to you. We may share Usage Information about visitors to a Site with third party advertising companies, analytics providers and other vendors for the same purposes.  We may use a variety of companies to serve our advertisements on other web sites, including Google. You may wish to visit **<http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>** , which provides information regarding the “opt-out” procedures of certain third party ad servers we use to serve our advertisements across the internet, including Google.

**CHANGING YOUR INFORMATION and updating your PREFERENCES AND SUBSCRIPTIONS**

You are responsible for maintaining the accuracy of the information you submit to us, such as your contact information provided as part of registration. The Redbox.com Site allows you to **_[correct or update](https://www.redbox.com/Account/YourAccount.aspx)_** certain Personal Information you have provided and to change your subscriptions or preferences regarding marketing information you receive from Redbox.  You may do so by logging in to your account and using the links provided on the “Your Account” or similar page of the Redbox.com Site.  Redbox will implement your requested changes in our active databases as soon as we reasonably can. When you edit your Personal Information or change your preferences on a Redbox Platform, information that you remove may persist internally for Redbox’s administrative purposes. Also, please note that it is not always possible to completely remove or delete all of your information from our databases and that residual data may remain on backup media or for other reasons. If you have made any public postings on a Redbox Platform, such as in Community Forums or other community sections of the Redbox Platform, these communications cannot generally be removed.

You may opt out of receiving marketing e-mails by following the opt-out instructions provided to you in those e-mails.  Please note that we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to your account or use of the Redbox Platforms or Redbox services, such as administrative and services announcements and these transactional account messages may be unaffected if you choose to opt out from marketing e-mails. If you sign up to receive SMS or MMS messages from Redbox, you may unsubscribe from any SMS or MMS messages received by replying “STOP”.

**YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their information is shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes. However, please note that under the law, a business is not required to provide this information if it permits California residents to opt in to, or opt out of, this type of sharing. Redbox qualifies for this alternative option. As described above, we will not share information about you with third parties for their direct marketing purposes without your consent. In addition, you can request that we stop future disclosures of your information for direct marketing purposes by contacting us at [questions@redbox.com](mailto:questions@redbox.com).

**THIRD PARTY CONTENT, LINKS TO THIRD PARTY SITES AND REDBOX CONTENT FOUND ON THIRD PARTY SITES**

The Redbox Platforms may contain content that is served by someone else or links to third party content or web sites that Redbox does not control. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and partners that may use our logo(s) as part of a co-branding relationship. In addition, Redbox widgets or other Redbox content may be included on web pages and web sites that are not associated with Redbox and over which we have no control. These third parties may send their own cookies to your Device, they may independently collect data or solicit Personal Information and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. Redbox is not responsible for the privacy practices employed by any third party.

**SECURITY**

Redbox takes commercially reasonable steps to protect and secure Personal Information. However, no data transmission over the Internet, by wireless transmission or any electronic storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  Please note that we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information we collect, and you use the Redbox Platforms and our services and provide us with your information at your own risk. 

**CONSENT TO TRANSFER**

The Sites are operated in the United States and Redbox operates its business in the United States. If you are located in the European Union, Canada or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect will be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using the Sites or our features or providing us with any information, you consent to this transfer, processing and storage of your information in the United States, a jurisdiction in which the privacy laws may not be as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside and/or are a citizen.  
V05_02_2013
